

DATA SCIENCE AND ANALYTICS LEADER

Chicago, IL, USA

📕 616.706.3471 | 💌 jim.kloet@gmail.com | 🖸 jimtheflash | 🛅 jimkloet | 💆 @jimkloet

## Summary\_

Hi, I'm Jim! I'm passionate about helping people and organizations make better decisions. So far, I've accomplished this by building and leading teams of talented data professionals across several industries, e-comm, consumer goods, healthcare, and academic research. Let's talk!

## **Experience**

Reverb Chicago, IL, USA

MANAGER, Product Analytics & Data Science

2021 - present

- I built a team of 6-7 data scientists and analysts supporting data science and analytics needs for product and eng teams, and senior leadership
- · We developed and support tooling to support running and analyzing 120-150 controlled A/B tests per year
- · We build and support machine learning models for 4-5 use cases across product, engineering, and marketing

ABC Supply Co. Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, IT Data Science

- Led data science initiatives across several domains, including workforce management, associate retention, security, and e-comm
- Developed project plans and supervise students and interns on capstone projects and hackathons with university partners
- Created and disseminated standards and best practices in data visualization and code management with R packages

Nielsen Chicago, IL, USA

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST, Data Science as a Service

2019 - 2019

2019 - 2021

- · Developed containerized pipelines to ETL data to and from AWS environments using python for a CPG client
- · Generated recommendations for optimal nationwide pricing and promotion strategies, delivered via Tableau dashboard

Mattersight Chicago, IL, USA

DIRECTOR OF INSIGHTS & ANALYTICS, SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

2015 - 2019

- · Led team of data scientists and analysts responsible for reporting and ad-hoc analysis for all subscription clients
- Developed analytic tools in R and SQL to scale implementation of best practices in statistical analyses and data visualization
- Automated client-facing reporting, enabling data scientists and analysts to reallocate hundreds of hours away from manual report generation
- · Led presentations for clients and internal audiences on development and use cases for predictive analytics, esp. predictive CX measures

RotoViz rotoviz.com

DIRECTOR OF VISUAL APPLICATIONS, CONTRIBUTING WRITER

2013 - 2019

- · Develop web applications to give users insights into performance of professional sports teams and players
- Train new writers and developers in data science and data visualization methods using R

Northwestern University Evanston, IL, USA

 $Translational\ Research\ Fellow,\ Doctoral\ Candidate,\ Research\ Technician,\ Communication\ Sciences\ \&\ Disorders$ 

2009 - 2015

- Designed, executed, and analyzed experiments to investigate language and learning in the brain using fMRI and rTMS
- · Presented experimental results at conferences, invited lectures, and in peer-reviewed publications
- · Delivered lectures to undergraduate and graduate students on topics in cognitive neuroscience and stats

Skills\_

**Programming** R, SQL, Python, git, Matlab, LTEX

**Big Data** Azure, DataBricks, Hive, Impala, Hue, Beeline

**Education** 

Northwestern University Evanston, IL, USA

 ${\sf MA, PhD} \ ({\sf ALL \; But \; Dissertation}), \textit{Cognitive Science, Communication Sciences \& Disorders}$ 

2015

University of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

BA, Psychology

OCTOBER 12, 2023 JIM KLOET RESUME